[
  {
    "quizTitle": "GIT",
    "quizQuestion": "What is Git primarily used for?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "Social Networking",
      "Version Control",
      "Online Shopping",
      "Video Streaming"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Version Control",
    "explanation": "Git is a version control system used for tracking changes in source code."
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "GIT",
    "quizQuestion": "What is the purpose of 'git add'?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "To create a new branch",
      "To commit changes",
      "To stage changes for commit",
      "To push changes to remote"
    ],
    "correctOption": " To stage changes for commit",
    "explanation": "git add is used to stage changes for the next commit."
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "GIT",
    "quizQuestion": "Which command initializes a new Git repository?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "git create",
      "git init",
      "git start",
      "git new"
    ],
    "correctOption": "git init",
    "explanation": "The git init command initializes a new Git repository."
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "GIT",
    "quizQuestion": "How do you commit changes in Git?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "git upload",
      "git save",
      "git commit",
      "git push"
    ],
    "correctOption": "git commit",
    "explanation": "The git commit command is used to commit staged changes."
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "GIT",
    "quizQuestion": "What does a Git branch represent?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "A specific commit",
      "A separate line of development",
      " A remote repository",
      "A Git user's identity"
    ],
    "correctOption": "A separate line of development",
    "explanation": "A Git branch represents a separate line of development."
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "GIT",
    "quizQuestion": "Which Git command is used to switch between branches?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "git switch",
      "git move",
      "git checkout",
      "git branch"
    ],
    "correctOption": "git checkout",
    "explanation": "The git checkout command is used to switch branches."
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "GIT",
    "quizQuestion": "What is a Git remote?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "A distant location",
      "A local directory",
      "A Git server",
      "A repository hosted on another server"
    ],
    "correctOption": "A repository hosted on another server",
    "explanation": "A Git remote is a repository hosted on another server."
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "GIT",
    "quizQuestion": "What is a Git pull request typically used for?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "Creating new branches",
      "Merging branches",
      "Proposing changes and code review",
      "Pushing changes to remote"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Proposing changes and code review",
    "explanation": "A pull request is used for proposing changes and code review on GitHub."
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "GIT",
    "quizQuestion": "How do you clone a remote Git repository to your local machine?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "git push",
      "git fetch",
      "git clone",
      "git pull"
    ],
    "correctOption": "git clone",
    "explanation": "The git clone command is used to clone a remote repository."
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "GIT",
    "quizQuestion": "What is Git 'stashing' used for?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "Deleting a branch",
      "Saving changes for later without committing them",
      "Creating new repositories",
      "Merging branches"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Saving changes for later without committing them",
    "explanation": "Stashing is used to save changes without committing them."
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "GIT",
    "quizQuestion": "Which Git command is used to view the commit history?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "git log",
      "git status",
      "git diff",
      "git branch"
    ],
    "correctOption": "git log",
    "explanation": "git log displays the commit history."
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "GIT",
    "quizQuestion": "What does a Git tag represent?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "A specific commit",
      "A remote repository",
      "A branch",
      "A significant point in history, like a release"
    ],
    "correctOption": "A significant point in history, like a release",
    "explanation": "A Git tag represents a significant point in history, often used for releases."
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "GIT",
    "quizQuestion": "How do you discard uncommitted changes in a Git file?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "git abandon",
      "git delete",
      "git discard",
      "git checkout -- <file>"
    ],
    "correctOption": "git checkout -- <file>",
    "explanation": "Use git checkout -- <file> to discard uncommitted changes in a file."
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "GIT",
    "quizQuestion": "What is the purpose of the .gitignore file in Git?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "To list contributors",
      "To specify ignored files and directories",
      "To track binary files",
      "To define remote repositories"
    ],
    "correctOption": "To specify ignored files and directories",
    "explanation": " The .gitignore file specifies files and directories to be ignored by Git."
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "GIT",
    "quizQuestion": "What does 'HEAD' represent in Git?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "The latest commit in a branch",
      "The name of a branch",
      "The remote repository",
      "The Git server"
    ],
    "correctOption": "The latest commit in a branch",
    "explanation": "HEAD points to the latest commit in the current branch."
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "GIT",
    "quizQuestion": "What is the purpose of 'git remote -v'?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "To view remote branches",
      "To view the Git version",
      "To view the remote repository URLs",
      "To view local branches"
    ],
    "correctOption": "To view the remote repository URLs",
    "explanation": "git remote -v displays the remote repository URLs."
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "GIT",
    "quizQuestion": "How do you rename a Git branch?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "git mv",
      "git rename",
      "git branch -m",
      "git branch -M"
    ],
    "correctOption": "git branch -M",
    "explanation": "Use git branch -M to rename a Git branch."
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "GIT",
    "quizQuestion": "What is a Git conflict?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "A disagreement between Git users",
      "An unresolved issue in a repository",
      "A situation where Git cannot automatically merge changes from different branches",
      "A bug in Git software"
    ],
    "correctOption": "A situation where Git cannot automatically merge changes from different branches",
    "explanation": "A Git conflict occurs when Git cannot automatically merge changes. "
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "GIT",
    "quizQuestion": "How do you resolve a Git conflict?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "By deleting the conflicting file",
      "By choosing one branch's changes over the other",
      "By canceling the merge",
      "By creating a new branch"
    ],
    "correctOption": "By choosing one branch's changes over the other",
    "explanation": "You resolve a Git conflict by choosing one branch's changes over the other."
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "git",
    "quizQuestion": "What is the purpose of 'git push'?",
    "quizOptions": [
      " To create a new branch",
      " To merge branches",
      " To send local commits to a remote repository",
      " To switch branches"
    ],
    "correctOption": " To send local commits to a remote repository",
    "explanation": "git push sends local commits to a remote repository."
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "GIT",
    "quizQuestion": "What does 'git rebase' do?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "Combines changes from one branch into another",
      "Moves commits to a new base commit",
      "Creates a new branch",
      "Deletes branches"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Moves commits to a new base commit",
    "explanation": "git rebase moves commits to a new base commit, often used for cleaning up commit history."
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "GIT",
    "quizQuestion": "What is the purpose of 'git reflog'?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "To log remote commits",
      "To log reference changes in the repository",
      "To log commit messages",
      "To log merge conflicts"
    ],
    "correctOption": "To log reference changes in the repository",
    "explanation": "git reflog logs reference changes, including commit changes in the repository."
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "GIT",
    "quizQuestion": "How do you update a Git submodule to the latest commit?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "git submodule pull",
      "git submodule sync",
      "git submodule update --recursive --remote",
      "git submodule fetch"
    ],
    "correctOption": "git submodule update --recursive --remote",
    "explanation": "Use git submodule update --recursive --remote to update submodules to the latest commit."
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "GIT",
    "quizQuestion": "What is a Git branch that serves as a base for merging called?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "Feature branch",
      "Master branch",
      "Integration branch",
      "Mainline branch"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Mainline branch",
    "explanation": "A mainline branch serves as a base for merging feature branches."
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "GIT",
    "quizQuestion": "What does 'git bisect' help with?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "Finding the oldest commit in a repository",
      "Identifying when a bug was introduced by performing a binary search on commits",
      "Listing all contributors to a repository",
      "Automating code reviews"
    ],
    "correctOption": "Identifying when a bug was introduced by performing a binary search on commits",
    "explanation": "git bisect is used to identify when a bug was introduced by performing a binary search on commits."
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "GIT",
    "quizQuestion": "What is the purpose of Git hooks?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "To create visual hooks in Git",
      "To prevent access to Git repositories",
      "To customize and automate tasks during Git events",
      "To manage Git remotes"
    ],
    "correctOption": "To customize and automate tasks during Git events",
    "explanation": "Git hooks are used to customize and automate tasks during Git events."
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "GIT",
    "quizQuestion": "What is Git LFS (Large File Storage) used for?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "To list large files in a repository",
      "To limit the number of large files in a repository",
      "To manage and store large binary files in Git repositories",
      "To create large text files in Git"
    ],
    "correctOption": "To manage and store large binary files in Git repositories",
    "explanation": "Git LFS is used to manage and store large binary files in Git repositories."
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "git",
    "quizQuestion": "What does \"squashing commits\" mean in Git?",
    "quizOptions": [
      " Combining multiple commits into a single commit with a consolidated message",
      " Creating a new branch",
      " Deleting all commits in a branch",
      " Creating a conflict in Git"
    ],
    "correctOption": " Combining multiple commits into a single commit with a consolidated message",
    "explanation": "Squashing commits combines multiple commits into a single commit with a consolidated message."
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "git",
    "quizQuestion": "What is a Git submodule?",
    "quizOptions": [
      " A directory with no files",
      " A repository embedded within another repository, preserving its own history",
      " A standalone Git repository",
      " A branch with a single commit"
    ],
    "correctOption": " A repository embedded within another repository, preserving its own history",
    "explanation": " A Git submodule is a repository embedded within another repository, preserving its own history."
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "git",
    "quizQuestion": "How do you set up global Git user credentials?",
    "quizOptions": [
      " git set user",
      "name \"Your Name\"",
      " git set credentials",
      " git user --global \"Your Name\""
    ],
    "correctOption": " git user --global \"Your Name\"",
    "explanation": "You set up global Git user credentials using git config --global user.name \"Your Name\"."
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "git",
    "quizQuestion": "What is the difference between 'git fetch' and 'git pull'?",
    "quizOptions": [
      "'git fetch' downloads changes and updates the working directory, while 'git pull' combines 'git fetch' and 'git merge' to update the working directory and the current branch",
      "'git fetch' updates the working directory, while 'git pull' updates the local repository.",
      "'git fetch' and 'git pull' are equivalent commands.",
      "'git fetch' and 'git pull' are unrelated Git commands."
    ],
    "correctOption": "'git fetch' downloads changes and updates the working directory, while 'git pull' combines 'git fetch' and 'git merge' to update the working directory and the current branch",
    "explanation": "\"git fetch\" downloads changes but does not update the working directory, while \"git pull\" combines \"git fetch\" and \"git merge\" to update both the working directory and the current branch."
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "git",
    "quizQuestion": "What is Git Cherry-Pick used for?",
    "quizOptions": [
      " To pick cherries from a tree",
      " To apply specific commits from one branch to another",
      " To merge all commits in a branch",
      " To create new branches"
    ],
    "correctOption": " To apply specific commits from one branch to another",
    "explanation": "Git Cherry-Pick is used to apply specific commits from one branch to another."
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "git",
    "quizQuestion": "What is a Git 'subtree' merge?",
    "quizOptions": [
      " Merging branches with similar content",
      " Merging subdirectories within a repository",
      " Merging two unrelated Git repositories",
      " Merging the history of a subtree of a repository into another repository"
    ],
    "correctOption": " Merging the history of a subtree of a repository into another repository",
    "explanation": "A Git \"subtree\" merge is used to merge the history of a subtree of a repository into another repository."
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "git",
    "quizQuestion": "What is the primary purpose of 'git submodules' over 'git subtree'?",
    "quizOptions": [
      " To simplify merging code from one repository into another",
      " To maintain a separate repository within the main repository while preserving its history",
      " To create a new Git branch",
      " To combine multiple repositories into a single repository"
    ],
    "correctOption": " To maintain a separate repository within the main repository while preserving its history",
    "explanation": "Git submodules are used to maintain a separate repository within the main repository while preserving its history."
  },
  {
    "quizTitle": "git",
    "quizQuestion": "What does 'git filter-branch' allow you to do?",
    "quizOptions": [
      " Filter commits to remove specific files or directories from the repository",
      " Filter out branches from a repository",
      " Filter commits based on author names",
      " Filter out merge commits from the commit history"
    ],
    "correctOption": " Filter commits to remove specific files or directories from the repository",
    "explanation": "'git filter-branch' allows you to filter commits to remove specific files or directories from the repository."
  }
]